SANTIAGO QUINTERO

DATA SCIENCE | DATA ENGINEERING

🕓 +57 3188621924 🛮 🖸 santiangr@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/santiangr

ABOUT ME

Mecatronics Engineer specialized in Data Analysis, Data Science and Data engineering. I have experience in fullstack web development and a passionate about artificial intelligence. I am a highly competent individual, capable of learning any technology swiftly. With an open mindset towards learning, I consistently seek to optimize corporate processes and tasks, leading to significant cost savings and improved efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

Performance Business Excellence Analyst Teleperformance Co. • Mar 2022 - today

- Designed and implemented an automated alert system for the Quality Department using Python. Data was consolidated into SQL for dashboard creation, leading to a 98% reduction in task time and generating annual savings of \$200,000 USD.
- Automated quality monitoring using Langchain Agents, trained with client data and leveraging APIs like OpenAI and SerpApi, resulting in annual savings of \$6 million USD.
- Implemented automated Value Stream Mapping in Python, utilizing Hugging Face's speaker classification and transcription models. This facilitated the automatic scoring for some KPIs, produced new insights for process improvement, fostered connections between different departments, and led to annual savings of \$300,000 USD.
- Developed an API based on advanced web scraping from the official city hall website to convert power outage news into actionable data, identifying neighborhoods with frequent issues. This refined contracting processes based on this variable, resulting in \$300,000 USD annual savings by reducing power outage events.
- Actively involved in innovative projects, data transformation, and creating links between different departments, enhancing and aligning processes.

Data Scientist Jr

Axelia Capital LLC • Oct 2021- Mar 2022

- Full-stack development of portfolio management tools using Reinforcement Learning models and their ongoing monitoring
- Development of specialized bots in financial investmet using AI, building from frontend to backend.
- Market analysis and forecast using ML, Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning.

Support and Analysis Engineer

Politecnico San Jose Calasanz • Jun 2021- Oct 2021

- Creation of automated dashboards to present results and analysis.
- Insights to segment advertising offers based on sociodemographic data.

SKILLS

Python - TensorFlow - Keras - NTLK -Pandas - Numpy - Langchain - SQL -SQL Server - My SQL - Postgres - Power BI - Airflow - ETL - Django Framework -JavaScript - TypeScript - React - Next Js - Next Auth - Node Js - Express - Prisma - CSS - HTML

EDUCATION

Mechatronics Engineering

Universidad Militar Nueva Granada 2016-2021

LANGUAGES

- English Conversational
- Spanish Native